Lucas Camponogara Viera

T (+886) 0979 235 851

■ monteirocamponogara@gmail.com

camponogaraviera

lucas-camponogara-viera-5319871b

Currently working with design and simulation of Josephson junction-based superconducting circuits as a roadmap for large-scale fault-tolerant Quantum Computing in the NISQ era. My research interests are mainly in the field of circuit Quantum Electrodynamics and quantum-classical Machine Learning. Notwithstanding, I am always keen to learn about related engineering and technology trends straddling multiple disciplines to enhance research skills and sharpen communication. My work experience includes machine learning applied to image processing (deblurring, denoising), computer vision (classification), and natural language processing (sentiment analysis), as well as software development for Bluetooth communication.

Education

National Taiwan Normal University - NTNU

Taipei, Taiwan 2020 - 2023 (Exp.)

- PHD DEGREE IN ELECTRO-OPTICAL ENGINEERING, FOCUS ON QUANTUM COMPUTING
- SUBJECT: DESIGN OF TRANSMON-BASED PROCESSORS FOR SUPERCONDUCTING QUANTUM COMPUTING

Federal University of Santa Maria - UFSM

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

• B.Sc. DEGREE IN CONTROL AND AUTOMATION ENGINEERING (INCOMPLETE)

2017 - 2018

COMPLETED 180 CREDITS OF COMPLEMENTARY COURSEWORK IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (MACHINE/DEEP LEARNING)

• Avg: 8.04/10

Federal University of Santa Maria - UFSM

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

• M.Sc. DEGREE IN PHYSICS, FOCUS ON QUANTUM INFORMATION

2015 – 2017

• THESIS: DISTRIBUTION AND QUANTUM COHERENCE MANIPULATION IN MULTI-QUDIT SYSTEMS

THESIS: DIMENSIONAL ASPECTS OF PHOTON MASS IN QUANTUM ELECTRODYNAMICS

• AVG: 7.7/10

Federal University of Santa Maria - UFSM

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

• B.Sc. DEGREE IN PHYSICS, FOCUS ON QUANTUM ELECTRODYNAMICS

2011 – 2015

• Avg: 7.59/10

Professional Experience

Research And Development Intern

INSTITUTION: NATIONAL TAIWAN NORMAL UNIVERSITY (NTNU) - TAIPEI, TAIWAN

Taipei, Taiwan, Sept. 2019 - Feb. 2020

• **Subject:** The internship consisted of the development of a Generative Adversarial Network (GAN) with Python, Keras and TensorFlow for the purpose of image deblurring.

Software Engineer

COMPANY: NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF SPATIAL RESEARCH (INPE) - SANTA MARIA, RS, BRAZIL

Brazil, July 2017 – January 2019

• **Subject:** The project consisted of the development of a GUI based automation software in python for research data acquisition through a secure Bluetooth Communication Client-Server Channel.

Awards

RoboWeek Challenge

Federal University of Rio Grande, RS,

Brazil

2ND PLACE OVERALL. DEVELOPMENT OF AN ALGORITHM (C++) TO DRIVING A TURTLEBOT INSIDE A MAZE ENVIRONMENT WITH THE AID OF LASER SENSORS. EVENT WEBSITE: HTTP://ROBOWEEK.C3.FURG.BR/

2018

MSc Scholarship Award (CNPq)

CNPQ, Brazilian Federal Research Funding Agency

Financial aid award for second-place overall in MSC entrance exam. Minimum award average of 70%

2015

2010

Inter-school Chess Championship

Santa Maria, RS, Brazil

2ND PLACE OVERALL. RESULT: 4-1-0. SWISS PÉTANQUE TOURNAMENT.

Publications _

L. V. Camponogara, "Distribution and Quantum Coherence Manipulation in Multi-Qudit Systems," M.S. Thesis, Ctr. of Nat. and Exct. Sciences., UFSM Univ., Santa Maria, RS, 2017.

L. V. Camponogara, "Dimensional Aspects of Photon Mass in Quantum Electrodynamics," B.S. Thesis, Ctr. of Nat. and Exct. Sciences., UFSM Univ., Santa Maria, RS, 2014.

Viera, L. C.; Muralikrishna, P.; Schuch, N. J.; Makita, K., "Study of Ionospheric Plasma in the South Atlantic Geomagnetic Anomaly Region," INPE/CNPq 114397/2011-2, 2012.

Technical Production

Baseline Architectures for Convolutional Denoising Autoencoder	Taipei, Taiwan
DESCRIPTION: MACHINE LEARNING ARCHITECTURE FOR IMAGE DENOISING WITH AUTOENCODER NEURAL NETWORK DEVELOPED IN PYTHON USING KERAS AND TENSORFLOW. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/AUTOENCODER/	2020
Autoencoder - A Comprehensive Guide	Taipei, Taiwan
DESCRIPTION: INVITED TALK ON DEEP LEARNING (2H). HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/INVITEDTALK/	2020
Red Blood Cell 3D-Surface Triangulation	Tainai Taiwan
 DESCRIPTION: A PYTHON IMPLEMENTATION OF EVANS, E. A., AND R. SKALAK (1980) RED BLOOD CELL MODEL FOR THE PURPOSE OF HOLOGRAPHIC TOMOGRAPHY. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/RED-BLOOD-CELL-3D-SURFACE/ 	Taipei, Taiwan 2019
Generator Network for an Image Deblurring GAN Architecture	Taipei, Taiwan
 DESCRIPTION: MACHINE LEARNING ARCHITECTURE FOR IMAGE DEBLURRING WITH A GENERATIVE ADVERSARIAL NET-WORK (GAN) FRAMEWORK DEVELOPED IN PYTHON USING KERAS AND TENSORFLOW. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/GAN/ 	2019
Logistic Regression Based Facial Expression Recognition	Santa Maria, RS, Brazil
 DESCRIPTION: MACHINE LEARNING ALGORITHM FOR CLASSIFYING HUMAN FACIAL EXPRESSIONS DEVELOPED IN PYTHON USING SCIKIT-LEARN. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/LOGISTICREGRESSION/ 	2018
Kinematic Algorithm for a TurtleBot in a Gazebo Environment	Rio Grande, RS, Brazil
 AWARD: SECOND PLACE MEDAL AWARDED TO OVERALL INDIVIDUAL TEAM WINNER OF A 24H ROBOTICS COMPETITION (ROBOWEEK) AT THE FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF RIO GRANDE (FURG), BRAZIL. DESCRIPTION: DEVELOPMENT OF AN ALGORITHM (C++) TO DRIVING A TURTLEBOT INSIDE A MAZE ENVIRONMENT WITH THE AID OF LASER SENSORS. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/ROBOWEEK-CHALLENGE/ 	2018
Sentiment Analysis using LSTM and Word2Vec	Santa Maria, RS, Brazil
DESCRIPTION: MACHINE LEARNING ALGORITHM WITH LSTM AND WORD2VEC DEVELOPED IN PYTHON USING KERAS AND TENSORFLOW FOR INSIGHTFUL TEXT ANALYSIS ON ATTITUDE SENTIMENT EXPRESSED IN A BLOCK OF TEXT. HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/MACHINE-LEARNING-ENGINEERING/	2018
Autonomous Software for data Acquisition via a Secure Bluetooth Communication Client-Server Channel	Santa Maria, RS, Brazil
 DESCRIPTION: GUI AUTOMATION SOFTWARE DEVELOPED IN PYTHON WITH BLUETOOTH COMMUNICATION FOR SENSOR DATA ACQUISITION. PLATFORM: WINDOWS HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/BLUETOOTH-COMMUNICATION/ 	2017
Snake Game - MVC Standard	Santa Maria, RS, Brazil
 DESCRIPTION: SNAKE GAME WITH AN INTERACTIVE MENU DEVELOPED IN PYTHON WITH PYGAME ENGINE AND MVC STANDARD. PLATFORM: DESKTOP HTTPS://CAMPONOGARAVIERA.GITHUB.IO/GAME-DEVELOPMENT/ 	2017
Supervised Teaching in Quantum Mechanics	Santa Maria, RS, Brazil
INSTITUTION: FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF SANTA MARIA WORKLOAD: 15H	2017
Technical Skills	
• Programming Languages: Python, MATLAB, C, HTML5, CSS.	

- Frameworks and Libraries: Tensorflow, Keras, scikit-learn, Qiskit, Cirq, sympy, Pygame, OpenCV.
- Others: Git, Linux, Android Studio, \LaTeX .

Languages _____

• Portuguese (Native); English (ILR Level 4); Spanish (Professional working prof.); German (Elementary prof.); Chinese (Elementary prof.).

Will be pleased to provide references upon request.